

Francesc Porta Solsona

Game Programmer

Parcelona, Spain

(+34) 660 57 52 39

Gamer, Dungeon Master, Musician, Basketball

HELLO!

I'm a passionate Game Programmer, proficient C++ programmer with 3 years of programming experience in several languages and software areas. As an image is better than a thousand words, I invite you to check out my portfolio here with my adventures as a Game Developer.

·PROFILES ·

GitHub



LinkedIn



Research Gate



·SKILLS·













arm



·LANGUAGES·

Catalan: Native Spanish: Native **English**: Professional working proficiency

French: B1.2

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UP2SMART INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGICAL SOLUTIONS, S.L. DATA ANALYST & AI DEVELOPER

September 2019 to August 2021

Tarragona, Spain

- Create predictive models using combination of Machine Learning systems to detect early Acromegally from faces in patient images.
- Research and document different prediction techniques to reccomend treatments (Health, Personal and Socially) for Social Service Centers.
- Develop a tool to analyse professional Data Bases automatically, with parsing obtained from the queries, and generate sheets with the relevant data.

1-ONE SANTÉ ET SECURITÉ AU TRAVAIL WEB DEVELOPER

Bordeaux, France

June 2015 to August 2015

• Develop various web tools and widgets for the company webpage.

EDUCATION

MASTER IN ADVANCED PROGRAMMING FOR AAA VIDEOGAMES

October 2020 to Present

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya (UPC), Barcelona

Master's Project: Develop a game using our own in-house Game Engine:

- QA LEAD: Coordination and mentoring of 15 programmers to meet the consistency, usability and scalability quality standards, both in coding and world-building.
- PROGRAMMER: 3D rendering using SDL, openGL and GLSL. Implementation of Bullet Physics library, ffmpeg video libary. Gameplay systems (Dialogue & Tutorials Manager, Game Controller, God Mode). "Multidisciplinar hand" in several other Engine and Gameplay features.
- GAME DESIGNER: Give context and coherence to the player and world narrative, and contributed to the full design of the Gameplay experience. (GDD wiki link). Communication tasks between different programmer, artist and leadership teams.

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2014 to June 2020

Tarragona, Spain

Universitat Rovira i Virgili, Tarragona

- Bachelor's degree Final Project: "Pectoral Muscle Segmentation" (<u>Paper</u> <u>App</u>)
- Notable projects:
 - Garlic arquitecture Processor with multithreading in C + ARM.
 - Californian car plate reader with Computer Vision in Matlab.
 - Custom language <-> C compiler in Lex + Bison

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Visit my portfolio for a quick overview on my work as game developer

D&D Backgrounds

BulKak - Rock Band

Guitarrist and web page author